For so long, emotions were seen as peripheral to the workplace and the idea that you shouldn't
bring your emotions to work was pervasive. And it's worth considering for a moment where this
view came from. There are two at least core historical reference points that we have for this
perspective. The first is the gendering of emotions. Dating back to the 1800s, we see how emotions
become feminized. And this is accounted to supposedly more masculine qualities like strategy
and logic. And this is then associated with over time the shift and the push of emotions out
of the workplace. And second, we see in the industrial revolution the push to mechanise and count
everything that can be mechanised and counted. And emotions are more difficult to mechanise
and count. And these two historical threads lead to a perpetuated view of this essential part of
human beings, their emotions as being unimportant. And it truthfully furthers a view that human beings
are resources. It's a dehumanisation. This comes at a cost because healthy organisations
and cultures where people feel connected and engaged are places where people feel that they are
able to bring the best of who they are, their full selves to the workplace. And this includes,
of course, their emotions. So healthy organisations are those organisations that are recentering
emotions where they should be. The heart of the organisation is found in the heart of its people.